<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Tirasa</title><link>http://www.tirasa.net</link><description>Open Source Excellence</description><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright 
          2016, Tirasa
        </copyright><generator>Hippo Cocoon Toolkit</generator><webMaster>webmaster@tirasa.net</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 10:08:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>http://blog.tirasa.net/images/logo.png</url><title>Tirasa logo</title><link>http://www.tirasa.net</link></image><item><title>Tale of a Twitter-based review</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/tale-of-a-twitter-based-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 11:28:10 +0200</pubDate><description>The uncommon chance to reply to an old review with fresh content. Via Twitter.</description></item><item><title>The new Apache Syncope Enduser</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-enduser-security-features.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 11:11:04 +0100</pubDate><description>Security-centric Enduser application enabled with CSRF / XSRF and CAPTCHA</description></item><item><title>The new Apache Syncope CLI client</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-cli-client.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 13:07:29 +0100</pubDate><description>If you are following the Apache Syncope dev mailing list you have seen different commits for the CLI admin tool. In this post we will discuss what the new client does and whish are the most useful features (of course from my point of view).</description></item><item><title>Custom policies with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/custom-policies-with-apache-syncope.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 16:20:16 +0200</pubDate><description>Need to comply with cumbersome account or password policies?</description></item><item><title>Migrating configuration chunks between Apache Syncope deployments</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/migrating-configuration-pieces-between-apache-syncope-deployments.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 10:27:58 +0200</pubDate><description>Moving Apache Syncope connectors and resources from one deployment to another</description></item><item><title>Run Apache Syncope and Docker</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-with-docker.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 13:42:48 +0200</pubDate><description>An introduction on how to run Syncope as a Docker application</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Spring's @Transactional</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/dynamic-springs--at-transactional.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 13:02:48 +0200</pubDate><description>Working ideas for pushing further Spring's declarative transaction management</description></item><item><title>Jasig CAS as SAML Service Provider</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/jasig-cas-as-saml-service-provider.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 13:19:28 +0200</pubDate><description>CAS is probably the most used open access manager, let's spice it with SAML 2.0.</description></item><item><title>Syncope on Centos via installer</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-1.2.4-on-centos-6.6-via-installer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 11:06:15 +0200</pubDate><description>A very practical sample for getting ready with latest Apache Syncope on Centos</description></item><item><title>Maven notifications under KDE</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/maven-notifications-under-kde.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 16:10:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Empowering KDE notifications for our beloved Maven builds.</description></item><item><title>Java library for Windows NT security descriptor management</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/ntsecuritydescripto-management.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Java library available to read and update Active Directory ntSecurityDescriptor attribute.</description></item><item><title>Adding approval processes on Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/approval-process-syncope.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The following post illustrates how you can create a custom approval process on Apache Syncope and use it for approving role requests</description></item><item><title>Wordpress and OpenAM SAML Federation</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/wordpress-and-openam-saml-federation.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 09:07:59 +0100</pubDate><description>Small example on how to federate OpenAM with Wordpress via SAML 2.0.</description></item><item><title>The Open (Source) Identity Stack</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/the-open-source-identity-stack.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 17:07:13 +0100</pubDate><description>Working on IAM you might have heard of the "Open Identity Stack": here's some Open Source alternatives</description></item><item><title>What's new in Syncope 1.2.0</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/whats-new-in-apache-syncope-1.2.0.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 15:31:59 +0200</pubDate><description>1.2.0 brings enhancements in several areas: REST, workflow, notifications, resource management, ...</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Apache Syncope on Debian</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/getting-started-with-apache-syncope-on-debian.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 14:14:28 +0200</pubDate><description>The upcoming new stable version 1.2.0 brings - among a whole lot of new features - the availability of .deb packages for getting started with Apache Syncope on Debian or Ubuntu.</description></item><item><title>Managing Hippo CMS users with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/managing-hippouser-with-apache-syncope.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><description>This post describes how to manage Hippo CMS users through Apache Syncope</description></item><item><title>Syncope Push and Matching Rules</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-push-and-matching-rules.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 11:52:11 +0200</pubDate><description>At last the possibility to synchronize data from Syncope towards external resources.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope at GitHub</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-at-github.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 11:33:18 +0200</pubDate><description>Besides "official" resources GitHub shows interesting Syncope derivative projects</description></item><item><title>How to get SSO in HippoCMS</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/hippocms-in-sso.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><description>As you can imagine this post is about Single Sign On and HippoCMS. In particular, at the end of this post, we will be able to deploy Hippo CMS in Single Sign On in our environment.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Apache Olingo on Android</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/playing-with-olingo-on-android.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Open data &amp; mobility: hot topics, in Open Source flavor.</description></item><item><title>Unlock full FreeIPA features in Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/unlock-full-freeipa-features.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 14:08:05 +0200</pubDate><description>Following our LDAP example, I tried to apply the same approach to the first beta release of  the new ConnId connector for FreeIPA.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.9 and 1.1.7 released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-9--1-1-7.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 10:20:52 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is pleased to announce the release of Syncope 1.0.9 (Espressivo) and 1.1.7 (Ad libitum): besides other things, these releases contain a security fix for CVE-2014-0111: upgrade from previous 1.0.X / 1.1.X versions is strongly suggested.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.6 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-6.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 17:31:59 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is pleased to announce the release of Syncope 1.1.6 (Ad libitum). This sixth maintenance version fixes few important bugs and introduces some interesting improvements: more details below.</description></item><item><title>Manage external resource provisioning directly with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/manage-external-resource-provisioning-directly.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 14:43:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The main purpose of identity management systems is to manage user and role provisioning. Provisioning operations can act on Apache Syncope only or be propagated towards external resources as well (propagation). Provisioning will occur on a certain external resource every time the operation involves users or roles assigned to that resource.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 2013: an yearly summary</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-2013-an-yearly.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 10:32:00 +0100</pubDate><description>End of year is time for balance, and mailing list discussion is probably the most important metrics of an open source project, at least when such project is part of The Apache Software Foundation, whose motto is Community over code.
            So why don't take a look at mailing list archives? Rob Weir did it recently for Apache OpenOffice and this was of inspiration for applying the same approach to Apache Syncope, using some good old shell scripting and Wordle app. Let's take a look at the results.</description></item><item><title>Install ConnId Connector Server as a Windows Service</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/install-connid-connector-server-as-a-service.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 11:29:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Java Connector Server is a component that handles Java Connectors bundles. When a Java Connector Bundle is not directly executed into Provisioning System (Apache Syncope), you need to use a remote Java Connector Server.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope virtual attributes</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-virtual-attributes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 10:36:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope virtual attributes are often a little bit hard to well understand. I hope this brief introduction can help.
            Any comments/remarks/suggestions are welcome.</description></item><item><title>Create PKCS12 client certificate via OpenSSL</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/create-pkcs12-client-certificate-via.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 16:04:00 +0100</pubDate><description>As is so often the case, working with SSL you need to configure and test a strong authentication (SSL client authentication). In all these cases, you need to provide an ad-hoc client certificate to perform a succesful handshake.</description></item><item><title>Create a new keystore to host a server ssl certificate</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/create-a-new-keystore-to.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 11:31:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Few basic steps to create a complete keystore to host a server certificate. Create your custom self-signed CA if not yet available a trusted one

            # openssl genrsa -des3 -out ca.key 1024
            # openssl req -new -x509 -day</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.5 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-5.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 16:57:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is pleased to announce the release of Syncope 1.1.5 (Ad libitum). This fifth maintenance version fixes few important bugs and introduces some interesting improvements: more details below.</description></item><item><title>Inhibiting line-wrap in ldapsearch output</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/inhibiting-line-wrap-in-ldapsearch.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:27:00 +0100</pubDate><description>As you should know, each ldapsearch line output is wrapped: the max size of a line output is of  79 characters. By the way, as is so often the case, ldapsearch output is retrieved to be automatically processed by a script or something else: in these cases the line wrapping usually is a big problem.</description></item><item><title>Configure Active Directory in Apache Syncope 1.1.5</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/configure-active-directory-external-resource.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope can manage users, groups and memberships (memberOf/members attribute) on external Active Directory via ConnId's Active Directory (JNDI) connector.    Think you manage users and roles on Apache Syncope as centralized IdM, and have all these entities automatically kept in sync with your Active Directory users and groups: few simple steps onto the Apache Syncope administration console will help you to succesfully aim your goals ....</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope: add user or role pre-processing mechanism</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-add-user-or-role-pre-processing-mechanism.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 11:12:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Before storing/propagating/synchronizing a specific user or role, a pre-processor can be called in order to allow any kind of manipulation before any actual operation takes place.</description></item><item><title>Manage Javascript and CSS dependencies via Maven</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/manage-javascript-and-css-dependencies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 10:08:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Every JEE developer will eventually need some Javascript &amp;amp; CSS spice in his applications: jQuery, jQuery UI, Bootstrap, AngularJS, highlight.js, YUI ...
            What's the usual solution? Grab files from somewhere and statically include them in your source tree.</description></item><item><title>OpenIAM Identity Manager vs Apache Syncope - first approach</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/openiam-identity-manager-vs-apache.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 15:26:00 +0100</pubDate><description>I've a keen interest in IAM solution also because I think that my first qualification is simply: IAM specialist. Today, googling idm open source I noticed that the first result occurrence (also in paid search results) is openiam identity manager, so, out of curiosity, I decided to install it.</description></item><item><title>Getting around Active Directory search size limit via ldapsearch</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/getting-around-active-directory-search.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:51:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Asking for a large set of results via ldapsearch to an Active Directory (AD) you will get a "size limit exceeded" error message. Searches of Active Directory performed without paging are limited to returning a maximum of the first 1000 records.</description></item><item><title>Document your RESTful API with Cocoon 3</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/document-your-restful-api-with.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 13:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>There are lots of ways of documenting RESTful APIs in Java: just google a bit and you will find the nice Enunciate and Swagger, for example. Such approachs, however, are often quite invasive and hardly customizable. Many providers - like as Apache CXF - are able to dynamically generate a WADL representation out of JAX-RS annotated classes: such XML representation can be easily put into an XSLT transformation in order to obtain some end-user REST documentation.</description></item><item><title>Is ForgeRock license really OpenSource?</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/is-it-opensource.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 09:42:00 +0200</pubDate><description>This morning, drinking coffee reading license.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.4 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-4.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 10:01:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the new maintenance release of Ad libitum.
            The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Java REST client library for Apache Syncope 1.2.0</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/java-rest-client-library-for.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 13:25:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Starting with recent SNAPSHOTs releases of 1.2.0, it has become fairly easy to call Apache Syncope via REST from your Java application.</description></item><item><title>Using 389 Directory Server with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/how-to-add-389-directory.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 10:24:00 +0200</pubDate><description>389 Directory Server is an Open Source LDAP server by Fedora, valid alternative to other implementations like as Apache DS, OpenLDAP or OpenDJ: let's see how to install it and use it with Apache Syncope.</description></item><item><title>How to store user password only on external resources with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/how-to-store-user-password.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 13:23:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Today we see how to create a user without saving the password in the Apache Syncope repository. The user password will be stored only on Active Directory.</description></item><item><title>Execute adamsync from another host with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/execute-adamsync-from-another-host.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 10:59:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Execute adamsync from another host with Apache Syncope.</description></item><item><title>Remember: hardware comes first</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/remember-hardware-comes-first.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 14:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>My work companion is still the good old HP Envy 14 1100 that I wrote about a while ago: it is getting old after 2 years and a half, of course, but Linux helps me keeping it young.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Microsoft Shared Folders</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-microsoft-shared.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 15:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Shared Folders  are used to manage shared resources over a network. Users may specify folders to share with other computers on a network. All computers on the network, depending on settings, may view and possibly modify the shared folder's content.</description></item><item><title>Rename ldap entry via ldapmodify</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/rename-ldap-entry-via-ldapmodify.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 15:41:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Wow, today I learned a wonderful thing: the ldif syntax to rename an ldap/AD entry. If you want to rename "mario.rossi" with "Mario Rossi" you can do the following.</description></item><item><title>Linux 3.10, the Radeon flicker-stopper</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/linux-3-10-the-flicker.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 08:58:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Yesterday my dearest Siduction made me dist-upgrade to latest Linux kernel 3.10. I must admit I was a bit afraid at first (you know, running a kernel sooooo recent on a Debian box always smells "atypical"...) but I was confident enough in the GRUB power to take the risk.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.2 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 08:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the new maintenance release of Ad libitum. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>How to customize Apache Syncope console</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/customize-your-apache-syncope-console.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 08:43:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Today, I want to change the color of Apache Syncope console. In particular, I like modify the green background of the console in blue.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.1 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-1.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:32:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the new maintenance release of Ad libitum. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Microsoft Exchange</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-microsoft-exchange.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 16:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Microsoft Exchange Server is a mail server, calendaring software and contact manager. It runs on Windows Server and it is one of the main elements present into a Microsoft infrastructure. It often happens that one of the first requirements of an identity manager project is to integrate Microsoft Exchange in order to manage, into the global/centralized user workflow, mailboxes and mail contacts as well.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and PowerShell scripts</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-powershell-scripts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 11:03:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Windows PowerShell is a command-line shell and scripting language designed especially for system administration. Its cmdlets let you manage computers and all server-side Microsoft applications (e.g. Exchange, SharePoint, FileServer, Active Directory, ...).</description></item><item><title>Unlock full LDAP features in Apache Syncope 1.1.0 Ad libitum</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/unlock-full-ldap-features-in.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 15:11:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope can manage users on external LDAP directory server since almost the beginning, via ConnId's LDAP connector.</description></item><item><title>Work with ConnID CMD connector</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/work-with-connid-cmd-connector.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:23:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Tirasa developed a new ConnID connector called ConnIDCMDBundle. This bundle is used to connect to Apache Syncope the resources that are managed by Bash or Powershell scripts. In this post I will explain how use it to execute the adamsync.ps1 in a remote contest.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.0 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 18:29:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the general availability of Apache Syncope 1.1.0 Ad libitum. Besides a considerable amount of fixed bugs and improvements, the major changes introduced with this release can be summarized as follows:</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.7﻿ (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-7.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:11:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the seventh maintenance release of Espressivo. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Lavorare su un progetto remoto con Netbeans</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/lavorare-su-un-progetto-remoto.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 11:14:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Ho appena avuto la necessità di lavorare su Netbeans su un progetto Java residente su una macchina remota. Ricordo l'esistenza di un plugin, ma non ricordo precisamente se questo esista su Netbeans o ci sia solo per Eclipse. Fortunatamente le due macchine in questione sono una Ubuntu e una Debian, quindi mi è bastato installare sul mio PC il pacchetto sshfs.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.6 (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-6.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 17:24:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the sixth maintenance release of Espressivo. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Netbeans mi stava bruciando il PC</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/netbeans-mi-stava-bruciando-il.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 17:36:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Questo è un tipico post inutile, ma dopo aver messo a repentaglio la vita del mio Dell e5520 ho bisogno di riportare quanto mi è successo. Il mio PC, Joda per gli amici, è proprio un PC in gamba, vivo senza un rene a causa del suo costo, ma devo dire che ne è valsa la pena fin da subito.</description></item><item><title>Jexl syntax example</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/jexl-syntax-example.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 16:59:00 +0100</pubDate><description>This post because I googled to find some Jexl syntax example but I didn't find it!</description></item><item><title>OpenSource in the era of Cloud</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/opensource-in-the-era-of.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:13:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Valentine's Day: in love with OpenSource My company Tirasa is definitely a small company. But we do love OpenSource, we've always loved it, even before becoming Tirasa. This is the reason why we have started an OpenSource project for building an Identity Manager, and subsequently brought it to the Apache Software Foundation.</description></item><item><title>Tooltip with Apache Wicket 6</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/tooltip-with-apache-wicket-6.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:56:00 +0100</pubDate><description>This is the code to create a tooltip with Apache Wicket and without Javascript ...</description></item><item><title>Tooltip con Apache Wicket 6</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/tooltip-con-apache-wicket-6.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:48:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Ecco il codice per creare un tooltip in Apache Wicket senza l'uso di Javascript.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Active Directory SSO: modifica del processo di autenticazione (2)</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-active-directory-4.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 17:31:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Eccoci al terzo appuntamento della saga sulla modifica del processo di autenticazione su Apache Syncope. Nel secondo post abbiamo visto cosa dover modificare sul core di Syncope; in questo post invece vedremo cosa si dovrà modificare sulla console per arrivare al traguardo.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Active Directory SSO: modify authentication process</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-active-directory-3.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 09:31:00 +0100</pubDate><description>This is the first post of a series on the same topic: an Apache Syncope overlay to perform single sign on between Active Diretory and Apache Syncope Console. in this post we start with configuration of Apache Syncope, to be more precise we analyze the steps to change the Syncope process authentication from Spring Securety to OpenAM</description></item><item><title>Eseguire comandi unix in Java</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/eseguire-comandi-unix-in-java.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 19:32:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Per lo sviluppo del connettore UNIX di ConnId avevo bisogno di una buona libreria che mi permettesse di eseguire da remoto dei comandi UNIX su server remoti.
            Dopo aver provato diverse librerie per l'esecuzione di comandi Unix in Java,  la mia scelta definitiva è caduta su vngx-jsch una libreria che, a detta dello sviluppatore, migliora la più famosa jsch.</description></item><item><title>Exec unix command with Java</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/exec-unix-command-with-java.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 19:32:00 +0100</pubDate><description>To develop Unix connector of ConnId framework, I needed a good java library to execute unix command on remote server.
            After several tests, I choose vngx-jsch, a library that, according to its developers, improves jsch library.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Active Directory SSO: modifica del processo di autenticazione</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-active-directory-2.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 15:57:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Dopo aver visto come configurare OpenAM per ottenere un modulo di autenticazione che faccia Single Sign On su un Active Directory e un Data Store che si occupi della lettura del profilo di un utente dallo stesso Active Directory,  con questo post passeremo alla configurazione di Apache Syncope.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Active Directory SSO: OpenAM configuration</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-active-directory-1.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 17:44:00 +0100</pubDate><description>This is first post of a series on the same topic: an Apache Syncope overlay to perform single sign on between Active Diretory and Apache Syncope Console. In this articles, we will analyze the different steps to have an user that, after his authentication on Windows PC, can access the Apache Syncope admin web console without further authentication.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Active Directory SSO: configurazione di OpenAM</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-active-directory.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 18:58:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Questo sarà il primo, di una serie di post, che avranno, come punto di arrivo, la realizzazione di un overlay di Syncope con la particolarità di essere in Single Sign On con un'istanza di Active Directory. Attraverso differenti passi, vedremo come arrivare ad avere un utente che, una volta autenticatosi su un PC windows con autenticazione a Dominio, potrà accedere sulla console di Syncope senza autenticarsi ulteriormente.</description></item><item><title>Chi è Milagros Diaz?</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/chi-e-milagros-diaz.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 01:04:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Andare su http://it.bing.com/translator Traduzione da automatico a italiano Da tradurre: Te echo de menos niñaaaa Tradotto: I miss you, meno milagrosdiaz_509@hotmail.com Qualsiasi altro carattere non genera la stessa traduzione.</description></item><item><title>Uno strano colloquio</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/uno-strano-colloquio.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Ne abbiamo valutati tanti di curriculum vitae e di candidati, ma una cosa del genere sicuramente non ce la dimenticheremo facilmente. La crisi pare colpisca proprio tutti. Partiamo da qualche giorno fa. Riceviamo un CV di un signore piuttosto anziano che si candidava per un posto da commerciale.</description></item><item><title>WebDav e Debian</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/webdav-e-debian.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 20:08:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Il nostro caro amministratore unico, non so se vi ho mai raccontato la storia che il detto "più unico che raro" è nato il giorno in cui Francesco è diventato per la prima volta amministratore unico di una società, quella che fu la ePosse. Messa da parte questa chicca di cultura generale, che ha fatto il nostro amministratore all'interno di Tirasa?</description></item><item><title>Riaccendiamolo</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/riaccendiamolo.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 01:07:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Dopo una lunga pausa è arrivato il momento di ricominciare a scrivere. Fondamentalmente ci sono due tipi di blog, quelli tematici e quelli personali; questi ultimi classificati anche come diari online. Visto che io faccio sempre le cose a modo mio, questo blog sarà una via di mezzo tra il personale e il tematico</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.4 (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-4.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 15:58:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the fourth maintenance release of Espressivo, the first after graduating from Incubator. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Java: guess content type of byte array</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/java-guess-content-type-of.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 14:36:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Maybe it is a not a common usecase, but I've just had need to know the content type of a bare byte[ ]. After been searching the whole Internet and evaluated dozens of utility libraries I finally ended up with a very simple but effective solution.</description></item><item><title>Implementing virtual resources in Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/implementing-virtual-resources-in-apache.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 09:35:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope user mailing list has been recently discussing about "virtual resources", e.g. resources to be used like as 'marker' for users and / or roles. Even though this aspect will be probably part of the process of adding access management features to Apache Syncope</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.2-incubating (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:13:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The second maintenance release is made available by the Apache Syncope team. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Windows Azure SQL Database sharding support for OpenJPA: first public release available</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/ms-sql-azure-sharding-support.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Federations in MS SQL Azure are a way to achieve greater scalability and performance from the database tier of your application through horizontal partitioning. One or more tables within a database are split by row and portioned across multiple databases (Federation members).</description></item><item><title>Configure your Test Mail Server for Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/configure-your-test-mail-server-for-apache-syncope.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><description>This post will show you how to create a mail server for test Apache Syncope notification.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.1-incubating (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-1.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 19:34:00 +0200</pubDate><description>After the 1.0.0-incubating, the first maintenance release is made available by the Apache Syncope team. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>OpenJPA Configuration Extension</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/openjpa-configuration-extension.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 09:41:00 +0200</pubDate><description>OpenJPA is an object-relational mapping (ORM) solution, open source (distributed under the Apache 2.0 Licence) and extremely extensible.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.0-incubating (Espressivo) released!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 11:37:00 +0200</pubDate><description>After 7 months of work the Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the final release of the first stable version since entering the Apache Incubator. This release took a bit more than expected because the team had to get familiar with new ASF procedures and toolset.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Oracle WebLogic 12c with Cargo Maven Plugin 1.2.2</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/controlling-oracle-weblogic-12c-with.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 17:12:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Cargo is a really nice piece of software that comes handy when developing web apps, by enabling deployment on a significant number of JEE containers at a very low price of some configuration parameters. The current version (1.2.2) has support for Oracle WebLogic up to 10.3.x; however, with some very little modifications it can handle 12c as well.</description></item><item><title>Apache fun: Cocoon 2.1.X and Tomcat 7</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-fun-cocoon-2-1.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 14:32:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Will you ever think to deploy a webapp based on the most diffuse and popular Apache Cocoon version (2.1) onto the most recent Apache Tomcat?
            Well, despite of the fact that the former reached its widest spread when the the latter's major version was 3, 4 or 5 at most, it is actually possible. Only, completely undocumented :-)</description></item><item><title>I fratelli più piccoli</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/i-fratelli-piu-piccoli.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 10:45:00 +0100</pubDate><description>“Ogni volta che avete fatto queste cose a uno solo di questi miei fratelli più piccoli, l'avete fatto a me.” (Mt 25, 40)
            E' quello che mi risuona in testa da ieri sera.
            Ho scritto e cancellato questo articolo ben tre volte: avevo raccontato cosa mi ha riportato alla mente queste parole, ma mi sono accorta che, concedendo troppi dettagli espliciti, ero scaduta nel luogo comune e avevo sminuito quello che volevo esprimere realmente.</description></item><item><title>The definitive guide to Maven projects with Eclipse IDE</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/the-definitive-guide-to-maven.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:25:00 +0100</pubDate><description>It's happened again: once in a while I must install the latest version of Eclipse IDE on my laptop, for various reasons (check some plugin, see how things look there, and so on).
            Hence, one more time, I come to Eclipse website, spend some nice time finding the right version for me, then download, uncompress, start. When it prompts for workspace location, an ancient image comes in front of my eyes and I start remembering Amiga workbench and its drawers...</description></item><item><title>Quelli che...</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/quelli-che.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 13:10:00 +0100</pubDate><description>...delle volte scruti con un sentimento struggente di ammirazione mista ad invidia, per come sono o per il modo in cui riescono ad amare così appassionatamente quello che fanno...</description></item><item><title>Data esecuzione comando</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/data-esecuzione-comando.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 16:44:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Io non so voi, ma a me è capitato millllioni di volte di chiedermi, ma a che ora ho eseguito questo comando? Beh, una soluzione l'ho finalmente trovata, o meglio, copiata :) Nel file .bash_login inserite...</description></item><item><title>OpenJPA 2.2.0 and Glassfish 3.1.1</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/openjpa-2-2-0-and.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 15:14:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Syncope recently gained official support for Glassfish 3.1.1: since the JPA layer did - again recently - move to Apache OpenJPA, we faced some issues when trying to deploy Syncope - as OpenJPA-powered web application - to Glassfish.</description></item><item><title>Chiamate REST su HTTPS</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/chiamate-rest-su-https.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 14:25:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Mi sto occupando dello sviluppo di un connettore per OpenAM. Per effettuare le varie operazioni, al posto di utilizzare il clientsdk, abbiamo scelto di usare le interfacce REST offerte da OpenAM; nel caso in cui quest'ultimo sia deployato in https, la chiamata restituisce un'eccezione del tipo:</description></item><item><title>Perché la cara vecchia Debian.</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/perche-la-cara-vecchia-debian.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 15:58:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Da quando lavoro, ovviamente, e non starò qui a spiegare l'ovviamente a cosa si riferisce (fare i discorsi scontati mi sembra superfluo), uso solamente macchine con Linux installato. Compro un PC, pulisco tutto, getto nel cesso non so quanti euro di licenza Windows PREPAGATA e installo la distribuzione di Linux che più preferisco.</description></item><item><title>Posso postare qualcosa che non c'entra niente?</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/posso-postare-qualcosa-che-non.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 18:42:00 +0100</pubDate><description>“Un Pazzo è un disadattato, un ribelle, un combina guai. 
            E’ disordinato, scapestrato, incosciente, 
            ride quando tutti piangono e piange quando tutti ridono.</description></item><item><title>Quando l'issue ti rovina le giornate!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/quando-l-issue-ti-rovina.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 14:48:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Come ci si può far rovinare tre giorni da un'issue? Basta avere a che fare con l'encoding e un DB criptato. Dopo tre giorni di analisi, mi sono accorto che il problema alla base dell'issue non era di basso livello, quindi su come certi dati venivano passati al DB, ma su</description></item><item><title>Come votare un sondaggio online...imbrogliando.</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/come-votare-un-sondaggio-online.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 09:44:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Avevo anticipato che prima o poi avrei fatto un post tecnico di qualche tipo. Ora, visto che una delle cose che più mi divertono del mio lavoro è lo sviluppo di script bash, vi posto quello che ho fatto ieri sera. Lo scopo di questo script, totalmente educativo, è quello di riuscire a effettuare una serie di votazioni online, ma su un sondaggio che permette una sola votazione al giorno. Per fare questo ho usato l'opzione del comando curl che permette di effettuare chiamate attraverso l'uso di proxy; e su internet ci sono molti proxy che vengono utilizzati per la navigazione anonima; tra questi ce ne era uno in particolare che ne forniva una corposa lista :)</description></item><item><title>Sempre su Facebook, ma non proprio</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/sempre-su-facebook-ma-non.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 17:46:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Qui a Campobasso nevica e nevica anche di brutto. E voi direte, e chissenefrega, e io vi dirò, ma chi v'ha chiesto di leggere quello che sto scrivendo?! Infatti aggiungo anche che domenica sono andato a fare snowboard e mi sono pure divertito, un pò meno il mio culo visto che ho una chiappa tumefatta.</description></item><item><title>Anche io soffro di Itso, devo ammetterlo</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/anche-io-soffro-di-itso.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 10:35:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Era una cosa che non volevo mai fare, ma visto che l'ha fatto lui, mi sono deciso a farlo anche io. Discutendo con i miei familiari, con i miei amici e soprattutto con il consiglio di amministrazione di Tirasa e con l'assemblea di tutti i soci, nonché con la segretaria, il tirocinante e la signora che pulisce le scale, mi sono convinto che devo curare la mia Itso. So che dice qualcosa a pochi, però è un disturbo di cui pare soffrano in molti, anche se non vogliono ammetterlo.</description></item><item><title>Syncope reviewed by one of its open source competitors!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-reviewed-by-one-of.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 10:24:00 +0100</pubDate><description>This morning I was looking at access statistics of syncope-idm.org, after yesterday great HOWTO about how to synchronize Active Directory and relational databases by using Syncope.</description></item><item><title>Le coincidenze del 10 Maggio 2011</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/le-coincidenze-del-10-maggio.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 11:49:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Questa data a molti non dirà nulla, fondamentalmente non dice niente neanche a me (l'ho dovuta cercare), però è una data molto importante per noi complottisti.
            Tra i tanti "misteri" irrisolti e sui quali si discute da mesi, anni, decenni, l'omicidio di JFK, è nato prima l'uovo o la gallina, l'attentato al Papa, le scie chimiche, il 2012 finisce il mondo, l'11 settembre, l'erba del vicino perché è sempre più verde, il sorriso da ebete della Gioconda, il sequestro Moro, ce n'è uno che parte proprio nella data del titolo, il 10 Maggio 2011. Cosa è successo quel giorno? E' successo questo!</description></item><item><title>Perché questo blog?</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/perche-questo-blog.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:07:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Non so scrivere, ma mi piace farlo. E' il modo attraverso cui riesco meglio ad esprimere ciò che penso, ciò che sento... da sempre. E' il modo attraverso cui, più spesso, ho detto a qualcuno “ti voglio bene” ... infantile? Può essere, ma se è vero che dovremmo tutti rimanere un po' bambini dentro, beh, questo è il mio modo di esserlo. In questo blog potete chiamarmi “milla”: qualcuno, anni fa, mi diede questo nomignolo come abbreviazione di camomilla: "Ti ho pensato e mi sono sentito tranquillo. Ti dispiace se ti chiamo Camomilla?"</description></item><item><title>Steve, pace fratello..</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/steve-pace-fratello.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 16:01:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Steve mio caro Steve, non ce l'ho direttamente con te, ci mancherebbe, tu hai fatto solo il tuo lavoro, hai fatto solo quello che si chiede di fare a un capo, far crescere la propria azienda fino a farla diventare quello che è ora Apple. Ora gli altri ti chiamano genio semplicemente perché non sono in grado di fare, con l'azienda che loro guidano, quello che sei riuscito a fare tu con la tua. E' una sorta di favola della volpe e l'uva, se non puoi ottenere una cosa la disprezzi, nel tuo caso si è trasformato in: se non puoi ottenere una cosa, chi la ottiene è un genio. Ma sarebbe dovuta essere: se non puoi ottenere una cosa, fatti un esame di coscienza, forse sei semplicemente mediocre.</description></item><item><title>Ma tu quanto sei social?</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/ma-tu-quanto-sei-social.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 14:12:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Sono entrato nel mondo di Twitter, chi l'avrebbe mai detto, e l'ho fatto alla grande, non riesco a immaginare minimamente cosa possa farci. Anche perché la cosa che mi sono sempre chiesto è, ma a chi mai dovrebbe fregare cosa faccio io? 10 minuti fa ero in bagno e volevo mandare un tweet del tipo, sto cagando, interessante vero?! Alla fine non l'ho fatto, avrei cominciato con il piede sbagliato!</description></item><item><title>(Finally) Spring, Quartz and JPA working together</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/finally-spring-quartz-and-jpa.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:56:00 +0100</pubDate><description>When writing Java code relying on Spring and JPA, you may eventually come to the need of some scheduling; since Quartz is by far the reference in this field, you think you will solve all of your problems by reading the appropriate page on Spring docs. Wrong, at least if you need some Spring goodies like @Autowired and @Transactional.</description></item><item><title>New release of ConnId Database Table Connector</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/new-release-of-connid-database.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 16:35:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Today ConnId Database Table connector version 2.0 has been released.
New features introduced are ...</description></item><item><title>Big mess solved, at last</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/big-mess-solved-at-last.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 10:51:00 +0100</pubDate><description>There are few years that I listen always the usual complains about the big mess caused by an uncorrect use of Active Directory groups in order to reflect own organization and manage access permissions to the resources.</description></item><item><title>Forbes intervista uno dei fondatori di Tirasa: Jobs voleva comprare Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/forbes-intervista-uno-dei-fondatori.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 15:22:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Di seguito l'intervista (parodia di questa ) rilasciata da uno dei fondatori di Tirasa alla rivista Forbes (G: Giornalista, M: fondatore di Tirasa; nell'intervista si scopre un retroscena di quelli che Maurizio Mosca avrebbe definito una bomba: Steve Jobs voleva comprare Syncope...e non solo!</description></item><item><title>Tablet e smartphone più venduti dei PC</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/tablet-e-smartphone-piu-venduti.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 10:24:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Oh, finalmente si è arrivati al bivio, finalmente saranno venduti più tablet che PC. Finalmente le persone si sono accorte che con l'uso che facevano di un PC bastava comprare un hardware di una calcolatrice anni '70 con uno schermo abbastanza grande per poter scrivere sulla propria bacheca di Facebook.</description></item><item><title>E se qualcuno avesse brevettato la ruota? Cosa penso dell'Open Source.</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/e-se-qualcuno-avesse-brevettato.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 14:11:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Bene o male tutti conosciamo i vantaggi e la storia dell'Open Source, soprattutto per chi lavora nel nostro settore; quindi, proprio perché non voglio scrivere di cose banali, mi evito tutta la manfrina del "è successo questo è successo quello".
            Lavoro, in un modo o in un altro, sull'Open Source ormai da diversi anni, questo ha fatto si che mi facessi un'idea su cosa sia e su come è cambiato il contesto che ruota intorno a questo mondo.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Activiti (and Maven)</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/getting-started-with-activiti-and.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 00:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Syncope needs a new workflow engine, for many good reasons: here's why I've started playing around with Activiti.

            Activiti looks really interesting because of features and Apache 2.0 license; moreover, its spicy story makes it even more attractive.</description></item><item><title>Cocoon 3 and Hippo CMS at work</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/cocoon-3-and-hippo-cms.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 15:43:00 +0200</pubDate><description>I recently presented some aspects of the renewed Apache Cocoon power through its latest (and not yet completed) release, 3.0.

            Today I am going to present some features of the Hippo Cocoon Toolkit, whose aim is to provide an alternative, Cocoon 3.0 based, toolkit for building front-end web sites while relying upon Hippo CMS and Repository.</description></item><item><title>AOP – Spring – JPA for background threads / jobs</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/aop-n-spring-n-jpa.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:48:00 +0200</pubDate><description>I've recently come up to a very wicked problem in Syncope, and a saving blog post pointed me in the right direction:
            Getting your persistence access right when working with background jobs in Spring can be tricky.</description></item><item><title>Build rich XML-enabled applications with Apache Cocoon 3.0 and Apache Wicket</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/build-rich-xml-enabled-applications.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 15:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Some articles are already around about Apache Cocoon 3.0, a deep rewrite of an Apache project that is bringing to the community innovative concepts since 1998.

            To be honest, the latest release is slowly approaching to a stable level, especially if compared to the wide spread and appreciation that 2.x series used to have - and still has, to a certain extent - all around the world.</description></item><item><title>HSQLDB 2.0.0, BLOB &amp;amp; Hibernate</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/hsqldb-2-0-0-blob.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 15:56:00 +0200</pubDate><description>HSQLDB is a very nice and complete all-Java DBMS, particularly useful when doing quick test-outs or maven tests. 
            A while ago, a bug has been discovered in release 2.0.0 that is causing issues with BLOB management: this is a considerable issue especially with @Lob fields in Hibernate.</description></item><item><title>Apache Cocoon PMC Member!!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-cocoon-pmc-member.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 16:20:00 +0100</pubDate><description>After very good news I have reported before, this morning I have received a very pleasant  e-mail saying that since today I have been accepted as member of the  Apache Cocoon PMC.    Wow, I am still astonished by all this new stuff :-)</description></item><item><title>Still surprised by Linux? Yeah :-)</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/still-surprised-by-linux-yeah.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 16:01:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Yesterday evening I had to print out a photo of my son: since the only ready PC in the neighbourhood was my brand new Linux powered laptop, I just plug in the USB cable of my HP Deskjet F300 all-in-one.</description></item><item><title>Apache Cocoon committer!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-cocoon-committer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 16:24:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Yes, it's true - I am still realizing, but it's definitely true:since last February 21st 2011 I have been granted committer rights at Apache Software Foundation, on the Cocoon3 project.</description></item><item><title>Linux Mint 10 KDE on HP Envy 14 1100</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/linux-mint-10-kde-on.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 16:27:00 +0100</pubDate><description>I come from four-in-a-row (very good) laptops made by mummy Apple: an iBook G3, a Powerbook G4, a MacBook Pro Core2Duo and another shining MacBook Pro, powered by dual-core i7 and SSD.
            Because of some relevant changes in my work life (I'll write something about it in the near future), I had to return to my former company the latest laptop - with some regrets, however, it's a damn powerful machine.</description></item></channel></rss>
