<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Tirasa</title><link>http://www.tirasa.net</link><description>Open Source Excellence</description><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright 
          2016, Tirasa
        </copyright><generator>Hippo Cocoon Toolkit</generator><webMaster>webmaster@tirasa.net</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 17:47:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>http://blog.tirasa.net/images/logo.png</url><title>Tirasa logo</title><link>http://www.tirasa.net</link></image><item><title>Java library for Windows NT security descriptor management</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/ntsecuritydescripto-management.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Java library available to read and update Active Directory ntSecurityDescriptor attribute.</description></item><item><title>Syncope Push and Matching Rules</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-push-and-matching-rules.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 11:52:11 +0200</pubDate><description>At last the possibility to synchronize data from Syncope towards external resources.</description></item><item><title>Manage external resource provisioning directly with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/manage-external-resource-provisioning-directly.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 14:43:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The main purpose of identity management systems is to manage user and role provisioning. Provisioning operations can act on Apache Syncope only or be propagated towards external resources as well (propagation). Provisioning will occur on a certain external resource every time the operation involves users or roles assigned to that resource.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope virtual attributes</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-virtual-attributes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 10:36:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope virtual attributes are often a little bit hard to well understand. I hope this brief introduction can help.
            Any comments/remarks/suggestions are welcome.</description></item><item><title>Create PKCS12 client certificate via OpenSSL</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/create-pkcs12-client-certificate-via.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 16:04:00 +0100</pubDate><description>As is so often the case, working with SSL you need to configure and test a strong authentication (SSL client authentication). In all these cases, you need to provide an ad-hoc client certificate to perform a succesful handshake.</description></item><item><title>Create a new keystore to host a server ssl certificate</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/create-a-new-keystore-to.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 11:31:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Few basic steps to create a complete keystore to host a server certificate. Create your custom self-signed CA if not yet available a trusted one

            # openssl genrsa -des3 -out ca.key 1024
            # openssl req -new -x509 -day</description></item><item><title>Inhibiting line-wrap in ldapsearch output</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/inhibiting-line-wrap-in-ldapsearch.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:27:00 +0100</pubDate><description>As you should know, each ldapsearch line output is wrapped: the max size of a line output is of  79 characters. By the way, as is so often the case, ldapsearch output is retrieved to be automatically processed by a script or something else: in these cases the line wrapping usually is a big problem.</description></item><item><title>Configure Active Directory in Apache Syncope 1.1.5</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/configure-active-directory-external-resource.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope can manage users, groups and memberships (memberOf/members attribute) on external Active Directory via ConnId's Active Directory (JNDI) connector.    Think you manage users and roles on Apache Syncope as centralized IdM, and have all these entities automatically kept in sync with your Active Directory users and groups: few simple steps onto the Apache Syncope administration console will help you to succesfully aim your goals ....</description></item><item><title>Getting around Active Directory search size limit via ldapsearch</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/getting-around-active-directory-search.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:51:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Asking for a large set of results via ldapsearch to an Active Directory (AD) you will get a "size limit exceeded" error message. Searches of Active Directory performed without paging are limited to returning a maximum of the first 1000 records.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Microsoft Shared Folders</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-microsoft-shared.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 15:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Shared Folders  are used to manage shared resources over a network. Users may specify folders to share with other computers on a network. All computers on the network, depending on settings, may view and possibly modify the shared folder's content.</description></item><item><title>Rename ldap entry via ldapmodify</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/rename-ldap-entry-via-ldapmodify.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 15:41:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Wow, today I learned a wonderful thing: the ldif syntax to rename an ldap/AD entry. If you want to rename "mario.rossi" with "Mario Rossi" you can do the following.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and Microsoft Exchange</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-microsoft-exchange.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 16:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Microsoft Exchange Server is a mail server, calendaring software and contact manager. It runs on Windows Server and it is one of the main elements present into a Microsoft infrastructure. It often happens that one of the first requirements of an identity manager project is to integrate Microsoft Exchange in order to manage, into the global/centralized user workflow, mailboxes and mail contacts as well.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope and PowerShell scripts</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-and-powershell-scripts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 11:03:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Windows PowerShell is a command-line shell and scripting language designed especially for system administration. Its cmdlets let you manage computers and all server-side Microsoft applications (e.g. Exchange, SharePoint, FileServer, Active Directory, ...).</description></item><item><title>OpenJPA Configuration Extension</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/openjpa-configuration-extension.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 09:41:00 +0200</pubDate><description>OpenJPA is an object-relational mapping (ORM) solution, open source (distributed under the Apache 2.0 Licence) and extremely extensible.</description></item><item><title>New release of ConnId Database Table Connector</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/new-release-of-connid-database.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 16:35:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Today ConnId Database Table connector version 2.0 has been released.
New features introduced are ...</description></item><item><title>Big mess solved, at last</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/big-mess-solved-at-last.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 10:51:00 +0100</pubDate><description>There are few years that I listen always the usual complains about the big mess caused by an uncorrect use of Active Directory groups in order to reflect own organization and manage access permissions to the resources.</description></item></channel></rss>
