<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Tirasa</title><link>http://www.tirasa.net</link><description>Open Source Excellence</description><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright 
          2015, Tirasa
        </copyright><generator>Hippo Cocoon Toolkit</generator><webMaster>webmaster@tirasa.net</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 17:24:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>http://blog.tirasa.net/images/logo.png</url><title>Tirasa logo</title><link>http://www.tirasa.net</link></image><item><title>Custom policies with Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/custom-policies-with-apache-syncope.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 16:20:16 +0200</pubDate><description>Need to comply with cumbersome account or password policies?</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Spring's @Transactional</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/dynamic-springs--at-transactional.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 13:02:48 +0200</pubDate><description>Working ideas for pushing further Spring's declarative transaction management</description></item><item><title>Syncope on Centos via installer</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-1.2.4-on-centos-6.6-via-installer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 11:06:15 +0200</pubDate><description>A very practical sample for getting ready with latest Apache Syncope on Centos</description></item><item><title>Maven notifications under KDE</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/maven-notifications-under-kde.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 16:10:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Empowering KDE notifications for our beloved Maven builds.</description></item><item><title>The Open (Source) Identity Stack</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/the-open-source-identity-stack.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 17:07:13 +0100</pubDate><description>Working on IAM you might have heard of the "Open Identity Stack": here's some Open Source alternatives</description></item><item><title>What's new in Syncope 1.2.0</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/whats-new-in-apache-syncope-1.2.0.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 15:31:59 +0200</pubDate><description>1.2.0 brings enhancements in several areas: REST, workflow, notifications, resource management, ...</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Apache Syncope on Debian</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/getting-started-with-apache-syncope-on-debian.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 14:14:28 +0200</pubDate><description>The upcoming new stable version 1.2.0 brings - among a whole lot of new features - the availability of .deb packages for getting started with Apache Syncope on Debian or Ubuntu.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope at GitHub</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-at-github.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 11:33:18 +0200</pubDate><description>Besides "official" resources GitHub shows interesting Syncope derivative projects</description></item><item><title>Playing with Apache Olingo on Android</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/playing-with-olingo-on-android.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Open data &amp; mobility: hot topics, in Open Source flavor.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.9 and 1.1.7 released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-9--1-1-7.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 10:20:52 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is pleased to announce the release of Syncope 1.0.9 (Espressivo) and 1.1.7 (Ad libitum): besides other things, these releases contain a security fix for CVE-2014-0111: upgrade from previous 1.0.X / 1.1.X versions is strongly suggested.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.6 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-6.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 17:31:59 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is pleased to announce the release of Syncope 1.1.6 (Ad libitum). This sixth maintenance version fixes few important bugs and introduces some interesting improvements: more details below.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 2013: an yearly summary</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-2013-an-yearly.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 10:32:00 +0100</pubDate><description>End of year is time for balance, and mailing list discussion is probably the most important metrics of an open source project, at least when such project is part of The Apache Software Foundation, whose motto is Community over code.
            So why don't take a look at mailing list archives? Rob Weir did it recently for Apache OpenOffice and this was of inspiration for applying the same approach to Apache Syncope, using some good old shell scripting and Wordle app. Let's take a look at the results.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.5 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-5.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 16:57:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is pleased to announce the release of Syncope 1.1.5 (Ad libitum). This fifth maintenance version fixes few important bugs and introduces some interesting improvements: more details below.</description></item><item><title>Manage Javascript and CSS dependencies via Maven</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/manage-javascript-and-css-dependencies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 10:08:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Every JEE developer will eventually need some Javascript &amp;amp; CSS spice in his applications: jQuery, jQuery UI, Bootstrap, AngularJS, highlight.js, YUI ...
            What's the usual solution? Grab files from somewhere and statically include them in your source tree.</description></item><item><title>Document your RESTful API with Cocoon 3</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/document-your-restful-api-with.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 13:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>There are lots of ways of documenting RESTful APIs in Java: just google a bit and you will find the nice Enunciate and Swagger, for example. Such approachs, however, are often quite invasive and hardly customizable. Many providers - like as Apache CXF - are able to dynamically generate a WADL representation out of JAX-RS annotated classes: such XML representation can be easily put into an XSLT transformation in order to obtain some end-user REST documentation.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.4 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-4.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 10:01:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the new maintenance release of Ad libitum.
            The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Java REST client library for Apache Syncope 1.2.0</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/java-rest-client-library-for.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 13:25:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Starting with recent SNAPSHOTs releases of 1.2.0, it has become fairly easy to call Apache Syncope via REST from your Java application.</description></item><item><title>Remember: hardware comes first</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/remember-hardware-comes-first.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 14:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>My work companion is still the good old HP Envy 14 1100 that I wrote about a while ago: it is getting old after 2 years and a half, of course, but Linux helps me keeping it young.</description></item><item><title>Linux 3.10, the Radeon flicker-stopper</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/linux-3-10-the-flicker.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 08:58:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Yesterday my dearest Siduction made me dist-upgrade to latest Linux kernel 3.10. I must admit I was a bit afraid at first (you know, running a kernel sooooo recent on a Debian box always smells "atypical"...) but I was confident enough in the GRUB power to take the risk.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.2 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 08:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the new maintenance release of Ad libitum. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.1 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1-1.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:32:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the new maintenance release of Ad libitum. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Unlock full LDAP features in Apache Syncope 1.1.0 Ad libitum</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/unlock-full-ldap-features-in.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 15:11:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope can manage users on external LDAP directory server since almost the beginning, via ConnId's LDAP connector.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.1.0 (Ad libitum) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 18:29:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the general availability of Apache Syncope 1.1.0 Ad libitum. Besides a considerable amount of fixed bugs and improvements, the major changes introduced with this release can be summarized as follows:</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.7﻿ (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-7.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:11:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the seventh maintenance release of Espressivo. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.6 (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-6.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 17:24:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the sixth maintenance release of Espressivo. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>OpenSource in the era of Cloud</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/opensource-in-the-era-of.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:13:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Valentine's Day: in love with OpenSource My company Tirasa is definitely a small company. But we do love OpenSource, we've always loved it, even before becoming Tirasa. This is the reason why we have started an OpenSource project for building an Identity Manager, and subsequently brought it to the Apache Software Foundation.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.4 (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-4.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 15:58:00 +0100</pubDate><description>The Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the availability of the fourth maintenance release of Espressivo, the first after graduating from Incubator. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Java: guess content type of byte array</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/java-guess-content-type-of.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 14:36:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Maybe it is a not a common usecase, but I've just had need to know the content type of a bare byte[ ]. After been searching the whole Internet and evaluated dozens of utility libraries I finally ended up with a very simple but effective solution.</description></item><item><title>Implementing virtual resources in Apache Syncope</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/implementing-virtual-resources-in-apache.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 09:35:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Apache Syncope user mailing list has been recently discussing about "virtual resources", e.g. resources to be used like as 'marker' for users and / or roles. Even though this aspect will be probably part of the process of adding access management features to Apache Syncope</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.2-incubating (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:13:00 +0200</pubDate><description>The second maintenance release is made available by the Apache Syncope team. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Windows Azure SQL Database sharding support for OpenJPA: first public release available</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/ms-sql-azure-sharding-support.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Federations in MS SQL Azure are a way to achieve greater scalability and performance from the database tier of your application through horizontal partitioning. One or more tables within a database are split by row and portioned across multiple databases (Federation members).</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.1-incubating (Espressivo) released</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0-1.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 19:34:00 +0200</pubDate><description>After the 1.0.0-incubating, the first maintenance release is made available by the Apache Syncope team. The release is available here. See release notes for more details.</description></item><item><title>Apache Syncope 1.0.0-incubating (Espressivo) released!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-syncope-1-0.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 11:37:00 +0200</pubDate><description>After 7 months of work the Apache Syncope team is proud to announce the final release of the first stable version since entering the Apache Incubator. This release took a bit more than expected because the team had to get familiar with new ASF procedures and toolset.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Oracle WebLogic 12c with Cargo Maven Plugin 1.2.2</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/controlling-oracle-weblogic-12c-with.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 17:12:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Cargo is a really nice piece of software that comes handy when developing web apps, by enabling deployment on a significant number of JEE containers at a very low price of some configuration parameters. The current version (1.2.2) has support for Oracle WebLogic up to 10.3.x; however, with some very little modifications it can handle 12c as well.</description></item><item><title>Apache fun: Cocoon 2.1.X and Tomcat 7</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-fun-cocoon-2-1.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 14:32:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Will you ever think to deploy a webapp based on the most diffuse and popular Apache Cocoon version (2.1) onto the most recent Apache Tomcat?
            Well, despite of the fact that the former reached its widest spread when the the latter's major version was 3, 4 or 5 at most, it is actually possible. Only, completely undocumented :-)</description></item><item><title>The definitive guide to Maven projects with Eclipse IDE</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/the-definitive-guide-to-maven.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:25:00 +0100</pubDate><description>It's happened again: once in a while I must install the latest version of Eclipse IDE on my laptop, for various reasons (check some plugin, see how things look there, and so on).
            Hence, one more time, I come to Eclipse website, spend some nice time finding the right version for me, then download, uncompress, start. When it prompts for workspace location, an ancient image comes in front of my eyes and I start remembering Amiga workbench and its drawers...</description></item><item><title>OpenJPA 2.2.0 and Glassfish 3.1.1</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/openjpa-2-2-0-and.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 15:14:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Syncope recently gained official support for Glassfish 3.1.1: since the JPA layer did - again recently - move to Apache OpenJPA, we faced some issues when trying to deploy Syncope - as OpenJPA-powered web application - to Glassfish.</description></item><item><title>Syncope reviewed by one of its open source competitors!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/syncope-reviewed-by-one-of.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 10:24:00 +0100</pubDate><description>This morning I was looking at access statistics of syncope-idm.org, after yesterday great HOWTO about how to synchronize Active Directory and relational databases by using Syncope.</description></item><item><title>(Finally) Spring, Quartz and JPA working together</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/finally-spring-quartz-and-jpa.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:56:00 +0100</pubDate><description>When writing Java code relying on Spring and JPA, you may eventually come to the need of some scheduling; since Quartz is by far the reference in this field, you think you will solve all of your problems by reading the appropriate page on Spring docs. Wrong, at least if you need some Spring goodies like @Autowired and @Transactional.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Activiti (and Maven)</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/getting-started-with-activiti-and.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 00:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Syncope needs a new workflow engine, for many good reasons: here's why I've started playing around with Activiti.

            Activiti looks really interesting because of features and Apache 2.0 license; moreover, its spicy story makes it even more attractive.</description></item><item><title>Cocoon 3 and Hippo CMS at work</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/cocoon-3-and-hippo-cms.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 15:43:00 +0200</pubDate><description>I recently presented some aspects of the renewed Apache Cocoon power through its latest (and not yet completed) release, 3.0.

            Today I am going to present some features of the Hippo Cocoon Toolkit, whose aim is to provide an alternative, Cocoon 3.0 based, toolkit for building front-end web sites while relying upon Hippo CMS and Repository.</description></item><item><title>AOP – Spring – JPA for background threads / jobs</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/aop-n-spring-n-jpa.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:48:00 +0200</pubDate><description>I've recently come up to a very wicked problem in Syncope, and a saving blog post pointed me in the right direction:
            Getting your persistence access right when working with background jobs in Spring can be tricky.</description></item><item><title>Build rich XML-enabled applications with Apache Cocoon 3.0 and Apache Wicket</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/build-rich-xml-enabled-applications.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 15:51:00 +0200</pubDate><description>Some articles are already around about Apache Cocoon 3.0, a deep rewrite of an Apache project that is bringing to the community innovative concepts since 1998.

            To be honest, the latest release is slowly approaching to a stable level, especially if compared to the wide spread and appreciation that 2.x series used to have - and still has, to a certain extent - all around the world.</description></item><item><title>HSQLDB 2.0.0, BLOB &amp;amp; Hibernate</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/hsqldb-2-0-0-blob.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 15:56:00 +0200</pubDate><description>HSQLDB is a very nice and complete all-Java DBMS, particularly useful when doing quick test-outs or maven tests. 
            A while ago, a bug has been discovered in release 2.0.0 that is causing issues with BLOB management: this is a considerable issue especially with @Lob fields in Hibernate.</description></item><item><title>Apache Cocoon PMC Member!!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-cocoon-pmc-member.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 16:20:00 +0100</pubDate><description>After very good news I have reported before, this morning I have received a very pleasant  e-mail saying that since today I have been accepted as member of the  Apache Cocoon PMC.    Wow, I am still astonished by all this new stuff :-)</description></item><item><title>Still surprised by Linux? Yeah :-)</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/still-surprised-by-linux-yeah.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 16:01:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Yesterday evening I had to print out a photo of my son: since the only ready PC in the neighbourhood was my brand new Linux powered laptop, I just plug in the USB cable of my HP Deskjet F300 all-in-one.</description></item><item><title>Apache Cocoon committer!</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/apache-cocoon-committer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 16:24:00 +0100</pubDate><description>Yes, it's true - I am still realizing, but it's definitely true:since last February 21st 2011 I have been granted committer rights at Apache Software Foundation, on the Cocoon3 project.</description></item><item><title>Linux Mint 10 KDE on HP Envy 14 1100</title><link>http://blog.tirasa.net/linux-mint-10-kde-on.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 16:27:00 +0100</pubDate><description>I come from four-in-a-row (very good) laptops made by mummy Apple: an iBook G3, a Powerbook G4, a MacBook Pro Core2Duo and another shining MacBook Pro, powered by dual-core i7 and SSD.
            Because of some relevant changes in my work life (I'll write something about it in the near future), I had to return to my former company the latest laptop - with some regrets, however, it's a damn powerful machine.</description></item></channel></rss>
